A Register of the Stephen J. Tonsor Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1958-1999 and undated. (Box 30)
  - "The Idea of Primitive Society and Natural Equality as Expressed in Hobbes, circa 1979. (Folder 40: 11)
    Holograph. Includes typescript question paper for History 391
  - "Educating the Children of the 'Me' Generation,", 1979 June 13. (Folder 40: 12)
  - "The Use and Abuse of Myth,", 1979 August 21. (Folder 40: 13)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes an article, "Myth: Some Philosophical Problems," Elisco Vivas, The Southern Review, 1970. Printed copy
  - Review of Martin Schmidt and Georg Schwaiger, editors, Kirchen und Liberalismus im 19. Jahrhundert, Catholic historical Review, 1979 October. (Folder 40: 14)
  - "A Few Unequal and Preliminary Thoughts,", 1979 December 3. (Folder 40: 15)
  - Review of Carl E. Schorske, Fin-de Siècle Vienna: Politics and Culture, Christian Science Monitor, 1979 December 3. (Folder 40: 16)
  - Review of Glen E. Thurow, "Abraham Lincoln and American Political Religion," Modern Age, 1979 Winter. (Folder 40: 17)
  - "Liberty and Equality as Absolutes," Modern Age, 1979 Winter. (Folder 40: 18)
    Printed copy and typescript. Includes one holograph copy with a different title, undated; clippings, 1977 September 8 and 24; and a letter from Allan C. Carlson, 1979 December 18
  - "The Use and Abuse of Myth," Intercollegiate Review, 1980 Spring. (Folder 40: 19)
  - "Equality: The Greek Historical Experience,", 1980 April 29. (Folder 40: 20)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes clipping and note
  - "Remarks for the Graduating Class of MacMurray College, Jacksonville, Illinois, 1980 May 25. (Folder 40: 21)
  - "Equality Reconsidered: Plato and the Sophists,", 1980 June 13. (Folder 40: 22)
  - "Aristotle and Alexander,", 1980 June 16. (Folder 40: 23)
  - "Equality: Rome and the Stoics,", 1980 June 27. (Folder 40: 24)
  - "Early Christianity and the Problem of Equality,", 1980 September 9. (Folder 40: 25)
  - Review of Rex F. Miller's Tocqueville, Bryce and the Redefinition of Equality in the Nineteenth Century, 1980 December 23. (Folder 40: 26)
  - "Technology and the Conservative Classical-Liberal Debate,", 1981 January 5. (Box-folder 41: 1)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes holograph fragment and printed matter
  - "Is it Possible to be both a Radical Christian and a Political and Cultural Conservative?" Conference on Faith and History session, American Historical Association annual meeting, Los Angeles, 1981 December 29. (Folder 41: 2)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes a letter from Richard V. Pierard, 1981 November 24, and related materials
  - Review of Julius Dorneich, Franz Josef Buss und die Katholische Bewegung in Baden, 1982 June 7. (Folder 41: 3)
    Galley
  - "A Modest Proposal,", 1983. (Folder 41: 4)
    Typescript and printed copy. Includes articles by others
  - "Some Reflections on the Fulbright Program," transatlantic dialogue on the "Value Basis of Mutual Understanding," Bonn, Germany, 1983 January 14-16. (Folder 41: 5)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes conference related materials
  - "Family Circle," reply to an article, National Review, 1983 March 18. (Folder 41: 6)
  - Review of Paul Gottfried, Hegel, Historicism and the Postwar American Right, 1984 August 21. (Folder 41: 7)
  - "The Medieval Model of Social Recontruction and the Nineteenth and Twentieth Century Reality," Catholicism in Crisis, 1984 December. (Folder 41: 8)
  - "Democracy in America at 150," Catholicism in Crisis, 1985 December. (Folder 41: 9)
  - "Why I too am not a Neo Conservative," National Review, 1986 June 20. (Folder 41: 10)
    Printed copy. Includes printed matter
  - Reply to a letter about "Why I am not a Neo Conservative?" National Review, 1986 July 18. (Folder 41: 11)
  - "The Hero and the Virtuoso: Renaissance and Sixteenth Century Anti-Egalitarianism,", 1987 February 26. (Folder 41: 12)
  - Review of Gleaves Whitney, Nietzsche's Mature Conception of Decadence, seminar, History 726, 1988 December 15. (Folder 41: 13)
    Holograph. Includes a typescript version of Gleaves Whitney's writing
  - "The Golden Bough or the Power of a Wrong Idea." University Press of America, circa 1989. (Folder 41: 14)
    Photocopy of a printed copy. Includes related material
  - "Christianity and the Second Religiosity" for presentation to a symposium of Modern Age on "Christianity in Sight of a Third Millenium,", 1989 May 24. (Folder 41: 15)
  - Review of James E. Crimmins, editor, Religion, Secularization and Political Thought: Thomas Hobbes to J. S. Mill, 1992(?) (Folder 41: 16)
    Typescript. Includes a letter from Horst Mewes, 1992 September 3
  - "The Enlightenment Reconsidered," paper, seminar on Christ Transforming Culture: Reflections on the Relationship between Faith and Culture, 1992 summer. (Folder 41: 17)
  - A Place Apart: The Traditional Ideal of Liberal Arts Education," first spring lecture, Faith and Culture Society, University of Michigan, 1996 January 24. (Folder 41: 18)
  - "A Tribute to Henry Regnery," speech, The St. Croix Review, 1996 October. (Folder 41: 19)
  - "Conservatism as a Creative Minority," Modern Age, 1998 Winter. (Folder 41: 20)
    Printed copy. Includes a letter by John M. Vella, 1997 November 19
  - "How does the Past become the Future? The Conservative Dilemma,", circa 1999. (Folder 41: 21)
    Holograph and typescript. Includes a letter from George A. Panichas
- University of Michigan File, 1940-1993 and undated. (Box 42)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, and printed matter relating to the administration of the university and the programs offered, course of study, final examination paper, and issues affecting the students, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General, 1967-1979 (Folder 42: 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated (Folder 42: 2)
    - 1958-1975 (Folder 42: 3)
    - 1976-1988 (Folder 42: 4)
  - Memoranda
    - Undated (Folder 42: 5)
    - 1966-1978 (Folder 42: 6)
    - 1981-1993 (Folder 42: 7)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1957-1978 (Folder 42: 8)
  - Notes, 1961-1986 (Folder 42: 9)
  - Printed matter, 1961-1975 (Folder 42: 10)
  - Programs file
    - Applications for summer faculty research fellowship, 1956, and faculty research grants, 1967 (Folder 42: 11)
    - Bicentennial Lecture series and Thomas Spencer Jerome lectures, undated, and panel discussion on Lincoln as a statesman, 1961 (Folder 42: 12)
    - Schedules, 1970-1984. (Folder 42: 13)
      Includes travel schedule
    - Statement by Dean Allen to the students, faculty, and staff of the Law School, 1970 March 28 (Folder 42: 14)
  - Teaching file
    - Course plans and examination papers, 1940-1988 (Folder 42: 15)
    - Curriculum vitae of applicants for various positions, undated (Folder 42: 16)
    - Faculty office hours, lists of committees and references, and students enrolled, 1978-1992 (Folder 42: 17)
    - Recommendations for students and grade reports, 1966-1993 (Folder 42: 18)
  - Miscellany, 1970-1975 and undated (Folder 42: 19)
- Writings by Others, 1952-2000 and undated. (Box 43)
  See also Correspondence
  Articles and books by individual authors, arranged alphabetically by name of author.
  - Unidentified, 1970-1997 and undated (Folder 43: 1-2)
  - Abulafia, David, 1977 (Folder 43: 3)
  - Amis, Kingsley, Undated (Folder 43: 4)
  - Berkhofer, Robert F., Jr., and others, 1978 (Folder 43: 5)
  - Bloomhardt, R. J., 1984 (Folder 43: 6)
  - Brooks, Harvey, 1971 (Folder 43: 7)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1952 (Folder 43: 8)
  - Carlson, Edgar M., Undated (Folder 43: 9)
  - Chitester, Bob, 1972 (Folder 43: 10)
  - Cutler, Richard L., undated (Folder 43: 11)
  - Dalrymple, Willard, 1972 (Folder 43: 12)
  - Decker, Fred W., undated (Folder 43: 13)
  - Elliott, Mark, undated (Folder 43: 14)
  - Evans, Stanton, 1981 (Folder 43: 15)
  - Francis, Samuel T., circa 1984 (Folder 43: 16)
  - Fleming, R. W., 1969 (Folder 43: 17)
  - Freeman, Roger A., undated (Folder 43: 18)
  - Gamson, Zelda F., undated (Folder 43: 19)
  - Genovese, Eugene D., circa 1969 (Folder 44: 26)
  - Giesey, Ralph E., 1985 (Folder 43: 20)
  - Gollin, James, undated (Folder 43: 21)
  - Greeley, Andrew M., 1981 (Folder 43: 22)
  - Hazlitt, Henry, 1971 (Folder 43: 23)
  - Heller, Erich, 1987 (Folder 43: 24)
  - Henrie, Mark Christopher, 1987 (Folder 43: 25)
  - Henry, Carl F. H., undated (Folder 43: 26)
  - Hirsch, Walter, 1958 (Folder 43: 27)
  - Hirshleifer, Jack, circa 1982 (Folder 43: 28)
  - Hollis, Martin (editor), 1985 (Folder 43: 29)
  - Holmes, Arthur F., 1969 (Folder 43: 30)
  - Hook, Sidney, undated (Folder 43: 31)
  - Houbeck, Robert L., Jr., 1984 (Folder 43: 32)
  - Ianni, Francis A. J., circa 1970 (Folder 43: 33)
  - Koslowski, Peter, 1982-1988 and undated (Folder 43: 34)
  - Lerch, Von Wolfgang Günter, 1989-1990 (Folder 43: 35)
  - Lukasiewicz, Mark; Czeslaw Kijanka; Jan Michal; and Tygodnik Mazowsze, 1984-1985 (Folder 43: 36)
  - McGowan, John, 1980 (Folder 43: 37)
  - McInnery, Ralph, 1976 (Folder 43: 38)
  - Maitre, H. Joachim, 1989-1990 (Folder 43: 39)
  - Martin, Michael C., undated (Folder 43: 40)
  - Masters, Roger D., undated (Folder 43: 41)
  - Miller, Arjay, undated (Folder 43: 42)
  - Opel, John R., 1982 (Folder 43: 43)
  - Paz, Octavio, 1987 (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Person, James E., Jr., undated (Folder 44: 2)
  - Picard, Max, undated (Folder 44: 3)
  - Regnery, Henry
    - undated (Folder 44: 4)
    - 1980-1981 (Folder 44: 5)
  - Rix, Walter T., 1990 (Folder 44: 6)
  - Robinson, Cyril Edward, undated (Folder 44: 7)
  - Sander, Hans-Dietrich, 1982 (Folder 44: 8)
  - Sandoz, Ellis, 1998 (Folder 44: 9)
  - Scattergood, Mary C., 1972 (Folder 44: 10)
  - Schnitzler, Heinrich, 2000 (Folder 44: 11)
  - Schoenberger, Bob, undated (Folder 44: 12)
  - Shell, Karl, Franklin M. Fisher, Duncan K. Foley, and Ann F. Friedlaender, 1968 (Folder 44: 13)
  - Shrodes, Caroline, Harry Finestone, and Michael Shugrue, undated (Folder 44: 14)
  - Silber, John R., 1971 (Folder 44: 15)
  - Silverman, Al, undated (Folder 44: 16)
  - Sobran, Joseph, 1991 (Folder 44: 17)
  - Sommerstein, Alan H., 1989 (Folder 44: 18)
  - Sykes, Charles J., undated (Folder 44: 19)
  - Thorson, Thomas Landon, circa 1972 (Folder 44: 20)
  - Thrupp, Sylvia L., undated (Folder 44: 21)
  - Trinkaus, Charles, circa 1981 (Folder 44: 22)
  - Vitali, Theodore, undated (Folder 44: 23)
  - Wallis, W. Allen, 1970 (Folder 44: 24)
  - Waugh, Auberon, 1983 (Folder 44: 25)
  - Widener, Alice, 1965-1969 (Folder 44: 27)
  - Universitas  Articles by a group of individuals, 1988 (Folder 44: 28)
- Subject File, 1961-1992 and undated. (Box 45)
  Annual reports, list, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletter, press release, printed matter, proposal, and schedule, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Annual report, form letters, list, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletter, press release, printed matter, program, proposal, and schedule.
    Includes notes and writings by others
  - American College Examination Board, 1970 (Folder 45: 1-2)
  - American Conservative Union, 1965-1970 (Folder 45: 3)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1980-1984 and undated (Folder 45: 4)
  - Blackburn College, 1972-1986 and undated (Folder 45: 5)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York, 1961-1981 (Folder 45: 6)
  - College Entrance Examination Board, 1970 and undated (Folder 45: 7)
  - Earhart Foundation, 1973-1985 and undated (Folder 45: 8-11)
  - Liberty Fund, Inc., 1982-1992 and undated (Folder 45: 12-14)
  - Mont Pelerin Society, 1966-1990 (Folder 45: 15-20)
  - Relm Foundation, 1969-1970 and undated (Folder 45: 21-22)
  - Open Court Publishing Company, 1970-1971 (Folder 45: 23)
  - Philadelphia Society, 1967-1995 and undated. (Folder 45: 24-29)
    Includes remarks by Henry Regnery and Stefan T. Possony, 1976
  - Stephen Decatur Society, undated (Folder 45: 30)
- Oversize Material, 1983. (Box 46)
  An article by Annelise Thimme published to celebrate a special occasion
  - "Friedrich Thimme und der Nationalsozialismus," Annelise Thimme, Antidorone: Festschrift für Jürgen Thimme zum 65. Geburtstag am 26. September 1982/herausgegeben von Dieter Metzler, Brinna Otto, Christof Müller-Wirth, 1983 (Folder 46: 1)
- Photographs, 1970-1988 and undated. (Box 47)
  98 prints and postcards depicting beautiful flowers, individuals, statues, and miscellaneous objects, arranged chronologically
  - 1 print depicting Juliana Pilon with a baby, undated (Folder 47: 1)
  - 4 prints depicting a church, a mountain range, a house with beautiful trees, and a group of unidentified people enjoying a party, undated (Folder 47: 2)
  - 1 print titled "Fear of Flying" depicting two young boys standing near an airplane, undated (Folder 47: 3)
  - 1 print depicting Whitney House Families after filming of Michigan DMH video "My Own Place," with narrator Chris Burke of TV series "Life Goes On,", undated (Folder 47: 4)
  - 23 prints from Annelise Thimme, including 19 depicting beautiful flowers, and 4 prints depicting kittens, undated (Folder 47: 5)
  - 1 book of 18 prints depicting flowers, kitten, house and the surroundings, undated (Folder 47: 6)
  - 25 miscellaneous prints and postcards depicting flowers, building, statues, and miscellany, undated (Folder 47: 7)
  - 1 print depicting the view from the porch of his house, undated (Folder 47: 8)
  - 1 print depicting Harry M. Clor, Irving Kristol, Robert Novak, Stephen J. Tonsor, and others, Public Affairs Conference, "Censorship and Freedom of Expression," Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio, 1970 (Folder 47: 9)
  - 2 prints depicting Phil Balla and his wife, Wanda, 1971 (Folder 47: 10)
  - 1 print depicting the garden at Meadowmere in Leroy gate, picking tomatoes, corn, beans, and grapes, 1973 (Folder 47: 11)
  - 8 prints depicting beautiful garden at Canary Islands including 1 depicting a woman and a child cleaning the ground, 1977 (Folder 47: 12)
  - 1 print depicting George Tilton playing with his dog, 1978 (Folder 47: 13)
  - 1 print depicting George Tilton with the "toy" at Carnegie, circa 1979 (Folder 47: 14)
  - 10 prints depicting a beautiful garden, entry door, and front yard of a house, circa 1983 (Folder 47: 15)
  - 10 prints depicting the beautiful house of George Tilton, circa 1983 (Folder 47: 16)
  - 1 print depicting a mountain range, circa 1986 (Folder 47: 17)
  - 2 prints depicting the front door and the backyard of the house of Frederick L van Holthoon, 1987 (Folder 47: 18)
  - 2 prints depicting Mr. and Mrs. George Tilton and with their son, John, 1987 (Folder 47: 19)
  - 2 prints depicting Jim, Drew, and Bun, Portland, Maine, 1988, and Stowe (Mrs. Bloomhardt(?)), Vermont (Folder 47: 20)
- Incremental materials (Box 48-49)